Carlos Villatoro

Full Stack Software Engineer

futurebound.carlosv@gmail.com, 832-866-1154, Houston,Tx <u>LinkedIn,Github</u>

Software Engineer that enjoys creative solutions to solve problems efficiently. With the ability to quickly learn and integrate, I am able to use my experience in fast-paced environments to meet client needs and changing deadlines. I will use my excellent communication skills and strong motivation to succeed as a team or individual.

SKILLS:

- Programming Languages: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Python, JSON
- Frameworks: React, Express, Django, Sequelize, Mongoose, Node.js
- Databases: MongoDB, PostgreSQL,
- API Implementation, Node is Packaging, Data Structures, JsonWebTokens, Hashing, Encryption
- Github, Git, Git Workflows, CSS Frameworks (Tailwind, Bootstrap), Authentication

PROJECTS:

- Nascar Pit Tryouts: An aim-based training game focused on using canvas DOM manipulation with JS. Built with HTMLICSSIJavascript. Deployed with github.io: Nascar Pit Tryouts
- <u>Carzilla Search</u>: A Node based full-stack application that implements a public API and Sequelize. Created with RESTful Routing to utilize the Sequelize ORM to create a database table structure and interact with relationally-stored data. Applies user authentication methods to authorize user actions by encrypting cookies during login and hashing passwords upon sign up. Deployed with Heroku: <u>Carzilla Search</u>
- <u>BugOut</u>: A collaborative React and Node based full-stack application that utilizes a React front-end user interface to update a MongoDB database using Node back-end routing. TailwindCSS was used to create a responsive single-page application. Deployed with Netlify: <u>BugOut</u>
 Personal responsibilities:
 - Managed front-end and back-end Github repositories by reviewing and approving pull request
 - Collaborated on back end and front end programming
 - Created responsive design using Tailwind framework

EXPERIENCE:

Software Engineering Immersive Student | General Assembly | Austin, Texas | April 2022 - July 2022

Completed a 12 week full-time immersive program in full-stack web development with 540 hours of expert-led instruction and project based learning in Javascript, Python, HTML and CSS with a focus on REST APIs and ReactJS.

Designer | Hudson Products Corporation / Chart Industries | Beasley, Texas | 2018 - 2022

Designed Air-Cooled Heat Exchangers using Engineered-to-Order specifications and API standards

- Completed full fabrication drawings including sheet metal and structural steel
- Reviewed design standards, procedures, and drawing output for deployment to manufacturing
- Represented engineering and design while consulting international manufacturing firms on material and design specifications

EDUCATION:

Software Engineering Immersive Student General Assembly | Austin, Texas | April 2022 - July 2022

Associate of Applied Science in Engineering Design Graphics San Jacinto Community College | Houston, Texas | May 2019